CONNOR O'ROURKE

Preston 07590659488

orourkeconnor@hotmail.co.uk

GitHub: https://github.com/CJOROURKE96

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I joined Northcoders to learn all I could about being a full-stack developer from a prestigious bootcamp provider in the North-West. Software development allows me to work with complex problems. Continue my learning within a collaborative environment while following agile methodologies to create a smoother user experience for the client.

Moving into the tech sector has allowed me to work with something I genuinely enjoy. The ability to make full-stack applications then see them used in real life cases is highly motivating. Being able to continue my own learning and development is another factor that attracted me to tech. I've begun to delve into C# to give me a grounding in a second language. As well as this I've begun to research AWS and general cloud principles.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Language: JavaScript

Front End: React | HTML5 | CSS3 | React Native | Svelte & SvelteKit

Back End: Express | SQL | MongoDB | Mongoose

Testing: Jest & Super Test

Additional Language: C# Learning since February 2023

EXPERIENCE

Northcoders

Junior Full-Stack Developer

November 2022 - March 2023

- Completed a 13-week bootcamp learning JavaScript, a selection of frameworks & libraries for both front-end & back-end. Giving me good grounding as a Full-Stack developer.
- Learnt industry best practices including, test driven development (TDD), pair programming & version control with Git. Allowing me to work collaboratively and output secure tested code.

Back-End project – Board Game Review App: A Back-End project using JavaScript, express & utilizing a Northcoders API to create end points for the Front-End to utilize. Completing full TDD in the process.

https://github.com/CJOROURKE96/BE-NC-Games-Project

- Front-End project Board Game Review App: A Front-End app using React & axios that
 utilizes the Back-End to create a smooth UI of board game reviews.
 https://github.com/CJOROURKE96/NC-Games
- Hosted Web App Board Game Review App: Built using the Front-End & Back-End projects
 via React. Utilizing MUI for Native compatibility.
 https://nc-board-games-reviews.netlify.app

Booth Air Conditioning

Engineering Assistant

January 2022 – October 2022

- Working with a variety of clients to resolve issues quickly. Giving me good client focused skills and the ability to understand a complex brief and output results in a fast-paced environment.
- Completing monthly maintenance reports, to reduce future breakdowns.
- Actively problem solving to complete complex tasks effectively & safely.

BAXI Boilers Manufacturer

August 2021 – January 2022

- Working as part of a large team to manufacture intricate mechanical parts. Communicating
 with a large group of colleagues across several different production lines to produce, word
 class quality products for the customer.
- Problem solving under pressure allowing completion of a build within the 87 second set time.

Sainsburys

Online General Assistant

April 2020 – July 2021

- Communicating with customers, colleagues, and third-party businesses to facilitate a smooth delivery process.
- Organizing daily workflows for other online colleagues.

Williams Estates

Sales & Lettings Negotiator

October 2018 – April 2020

- Creating detail focused brochures to market properties from vendors specifications.
- Pro-actively working to generate sales leads & hit targets.

Hospitality Bar Staff

March 2013 - October 2018

• Being customer focused, to enhance revenue streams by creating a loyal customer base.

QUALIFICATIONS

- BA Hons Religion, Culture & Society September 2014 – May 2018
- A Level Religious Studies (B) | A Level History (C) | A Level Welsh Second Language (D)
 September 2012 July 2014
- GCSE Maths (C) | GCSE English (B) September 2010 – July 2012

INTERESTS

- Tinkering with hardware, I have built PCs for myself & friends previously.
- Personal development, learning new skills & researching information on software.